<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>
<!-- revision 9597 -->

<sect1 id="ch-scripts-network">
  <?dbhtml filename="network.html"?>

  <!-- <title>General Network Configuration</title> -->
  <title>一般的なネットワーク設定</title>

  <indexterm zone="ch-scripts-network">
    <primary sortas="d-network">network</primary>
  <secondary>configuring</secondary></indexterm>

  <para>This section only applies if a network card is to be
  configured.</para>
  <para>ネットワークカードを設定する場合のみ、このセクションの手順を行ってください。</para>

  <para>If a network card will not be used, there is likely no need to
  create any configuration files relating to network cards. If that is
  the case, remove the <filename class="symlink">network</filename>
  symlinks from all run-level directories (<filename
  class="directory">/etc/rc.d/rc*.d</filename>).</para>
  <para>もしネットワークカードを使用するつもりがないのであれば、ネットワークカードに関する設定ファイルを作成する必要はないと思います。
  もしそうであれば、全てのrun-levelディレクトリ(<filename class="directory">/etc/rc.d/rc*.d</filename>)から、シンボリックリンク<filename class="symlink">network</filename>を削除してください。</para>

  <sect2>
    <!--<title>Creating stable names for network interfaces</title>-->
    <title>ネットワークインタフェースに固定的な名前を付ける</title>

    <para>If there is only one network interface in the system to be 
    configured, this section is optional, although it will never be wrong to do 
    it.  In many cases (e.g. a laptop with a wireless and a wired interface), 
    accomplishing the configuration in this section is necessary.</para>
    <para>もし設定するネットワークインタフェースがたった一つの場合、このセクションは任意となります(実行しても問題はありませんが)。
    多くのケースにおいて(例：無線と有線の両方を持つノートPC)、このセクションの設定を完了することが必要です。</para>

    <para>With Udev and modular network drivers, the network interface numbering
    is not persistent across reboots by default, because the drivers are loaded
    in parallel and, thus, in random order. For example, on a computer having
    two network cards made by Intel and Realtek, the network card manufactured
    by Intel may become <filename class="devicefile">eth0</filename> and the
    Realtek card becomes  <filename class="devicefile">eth1</filename>. In some
    cases, after a reboot the cards get renumbered the other way around. To
    avoid this, Udev comes with a script and some rules to assign stable names
    to network cards based on their MAC address.</para>
    <para>Udevとmodularネットワークドライバにおいて、ネットワークインタフェースの番号付けは、デフォルトではブート毎に固定されません。
    なぜなら、ドライバは並行してロードされ、その結果ランダムな順番で認識されるからです。
    例えば、コンピュータにIntelとRealtekの2つのネットワークカードが存在している場合、Intelの方が<filename class="devicefile">eth0</filename>で、Realtekが<filename class="devicefile">eth1</filename>と認識されるかもしれません。
    リブートの後、カードには異なった順番で番号付けされることがあります。
    これを避けるには、Udevに付属するスクリプトと、MACアドレスによってネットワークカードに固定的な名称を割り当てるルールを作る方法があります。</para>

    <para>Pre-generate the rules to ensure the same names get assigned to the
    same devices at every boot, including the first:</para>
    <para>ブートの際、デバイスに同じ名称を割り付けるルールを事前に作成します：</para>

<screen><userinput>for NIC in /sys/class/net/* ; do
    INTERFACE=${NIC##*/} udevadm test --action=add $NIC
done</userinput></screen>

    <para>Now, inspect the <filename>/etc/udev/rules.d/70-persistent-net.rules</filename>
    file, to find out which name was assigned to which network device:</para>
    <para>では、<filename>/etc/udev/rules.d/70-persistent-net.rules</filename>の内容を確認し、どのネットワークデバイスにどの名称が割り付けられているか調べます：</para>

<screen><userinput>cat /etc/udev/rules.d/70-persistent-net.rules</userinput></screen>

    <para>The file begins with a comment block followed by two lines for each
    NIC. The first line for each NIC is a commented description showing its
    hardware IDs (e.g. its PCI vendor and device IDs, if it's a PCI card),
    along with its driver in parentheses, if the driver can be found. Neither
    the hardware ID nor the driver is used to determine which name to give an
    interface; this information is only for reference. The second line is the
    Udev rule that matches this NIC and actually assigns it a name.</para>
    <para>このファイルは、1枚のNICに対して2行のコメント行で始まります。
    それぞれのNICの最初の行はコメントで、そのハードウェアID(例えば、PCIカードであればベンダーとデバイスID)、ドライバが見つかれば、カッコ内にそのドライバ名が記述されています。
    ハードウェアIDもドライバも、インタフェースに与える名称を決めるためには使用されません。この情報は参照するためだけのものです。
    2行目は、そのNICにマッチしたUdevルールと実際にNICに割り当てた名称です。</para>

    <para>All Udev rules are made up of several keys, separated by commas and
    optional whitespace. This rule's keys and an explanation of each of them
    are as follows:</para>
    <para>Udevルールはカンマと任意のスペースで区切られた、いくつかのキーから構成されています。
    キーとそれぞれの説明は以下のとおりです：</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><literal>SUBSYSTEM=="net"</literal> - This tells Udev to ignore
        devices that are not network cards.</para>
        <para><literal>SUBSYSTEM=="net"</literal> - Udevに対して、ネットワークカードではないデバイスを無視するように指示します。</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem> 
        <para><literal>ACTION=="add"</literal> - This tells Udev to ignore this 
        rule for a uevent that isn't an add ("remove" and "change" uevents also 
        happen, but don't need to rename network interfaces).</para>
        <para><literal>ACTION=="add"</literal> - Udevに対して、追加ではないueventに対するルールを無視するように指示します。
        ("remove"と"change" ueventも発生しますが、ネットワークインタフェース名を変更する必要はありません)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><literal>DRIVERS=="?*"</literal> - This exists so that Udev will
        ignore VLAN or bridge sub-interfaces (because these sub-interfaces do
        not have drivers). These sub-interfaces are skipped because the name
        that would be assigned would collide with their parent devices.</para>
        <para><literal>DRIVERS=="?*"</literal> - UdevがVLANまたはbridgeサブインタフェース(これらサブインタフェースはドライバを持ちません)を無視するようにするため、この設定が存在します。
        これらサブインタフェースは、割り付けられる名称が親デバイスと衝突するためスキップされます。</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><literal>ATTRS{address}</literal> - The value of this key is the
        NIC's MAC address.</para>
        <para><literal>ATTRS{address}</literal> - このキーの値は、NICのMACアドレスです。</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem> 
        <para><literal>ATTR{type}=="1"</literal> - This ensures the rule only 
        matches the primary interface in the case of certain wireless drivers, 
        which create multiple virtual interfaces. The secondary interfaces are 
        skipped for the same reason that VLAN and bridge sub-interfaces are 
        skipped: there would be a name collision otherwise.</para>
        <para><literal>ATTR{type}=="1"</literal> - 複数の仮想インタフェースを作るような、特定のワイヤレスドライバにおいて、プライマリインタフェースだけにマッチすることを保証します。
        VLANやブリッジ・サブインタフェースがスキップされることと同じ理由で、セカンダリインタフェースはスキップされます。さもなければ名称の衝突が起こります。</para>
      </listitem> 
      <listitem> 
        <para><literal>KERNEL=="eth*"</literal> - This key was added to the 
        Udev rule generator to handle machines that have multiple network 
        interfaces, all with the same MAC address (the PS3 is one such 
        machine).  If the independent interfaces have different basenames, 
        this key will allow Udev to tell them apart.  This is generally not 
        necessary for most Linux From Scratch users, but does not hurt.</para>
        <para><literal>KERNEL=="eth*"</literal> - 同じMACアドレスである複数のネットワークインタフェースを持つマシンに対処するため、Udevルール・ジェネレータにこのキーが追加されました(例えば、PS3がそのようなマシンです)。
        もしそれぞれの独立したインタフェースが異なるベースネームを持つ場合、このキーによってUdevがそれらインタフェースを区別するようにします。
        ほとんどのLinux From Scratchのユーザにとって、通常はこの設定は不要ですが、設定が存在しても害はありません。</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><literal>NAME</literal> - The value of this key is the name that
        Udev will assign to this interface.</para>
        <para><literal>NAME</literal> - このキーの値は、Udevがこのインタフェースに割り当てようとする名称です。</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The value of <literal>NAME</literal> is the important part. Make sure
    you know which name has been assigned to each of your network cards before
    proceeding, and be sure to use that <literal>NAME</literal> value when
    creating your configuration files below.</para>
    <para><literal>NAME</literal>の値は重要な役目をします。
    処理の前にネットワークカードそれぞれにどの名称が割り当てられるか確認してください。
    そして以下のとおり設定ファイルを作成するときに、必ずその<literal>NAME</literal>の値を使用してください。
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <!--<title>Creating Network Interface Configuration Files</title>-->
    <title>ネットワークインタフェースの設定ファイルの作成</title>

    <para>Which interfaces are brought up and down by the network script
    depends on the files in <filename
    class="directory">/etc/sysconfig/</filename>.  This directory should
    contain a file for each interface to be configured, such as
    <filename>ifconfig.xyz</filename>, where <quote>xyz</quote> is
    meaningful to the administrator such as the device name (e.g. eth0).
    Inside this file are attributes to this interface, such as its IP
    address(es), subnet masks, and so forth.  It is necessary that
    the stem of the filename be <emphasis>ifconfig</emphasis>.</para>
    <para>ネットワークスクリプトによってどのインタフェースが起動・停止されるかは、<filename class="directory">/etc/sysconfig/</filename>にあるファイルによって決まります。
    このディレクトリに、設定するそれぞれのインタフェースごとに、<filename>ifconfig.xyz</filename>の形式のファイルを置く必要があります。
    <quote>xyz</quote>は、デバイス名(例：eth0)のような管理者にとって意味のある文字列です。
    このファイルの中には、IPアドレスやサブネットマスクなどのインタフェースの属性値を記述します。
    ファイル名の始まりは、<emphasis>ifconfig</emphasis>です。</para>

    <para>The following command creates a sample file for the
    <emphasis>eth0</emphasis> device with a static IP address:</para>
    <para>次のコマンドは、固定IPアドレスの<emphasis>eth0</emphasis>に対するサンプル設定ファイルを作成します：</para>

<screen><userinput>cd /etc/sysconfig/
cat &gt; ifconfig.eth0 &lt;&lt; "EOF"
<literal>ONBOOT=yes
IFACE=eth0
SERVICE=ipv4-static
IP=192.168.1.1
GATEWAY=192.168.1.2
PREFIX=24
BROADCAST=192.168.1.255</literal>
EOF</userinput></screen>

    <para>The values of these variables must be changed in every file to match
    the proper setup.</para>
    <para>これら変数の値は、正しい設定に合わせるため、それぞれのファイルを変更する必要があります。</para>

    <para>If the <envar>ONBOOT</envar> variable is set to <quote>yes</quote> the
    network script will bring up the Network Interface Card (NIC) during
    booting of the system. If set to anything but <quote>yes</quote> the NIC
    will be ignored by the network script and not be automatically brought up.
    The interface can be manually started or stopped with the
    <command>ifup</command> and <command>ifdown</command> commands.</para>
    <para>もし<envar>ONBOOT</envar>が<quote>yes</quote>に設定されている場合、ネットワークスクリプトはブート時にNIC(Network Interface Card)を起動します。
    もし<quote>yes</quote>以外に設定されている場合は、NICはネットワークスクリプトから無視され、自動的に起動されません。
    インタフェースは、<command>ifup</command>・<command>ifdown</command>コマンドを使用して、手動で起動・停止することが出来ます。</para>

    <para>The <envar>SERVICE</envar> variable defines the method used for
    obtaining the IP address. The LFS-Bootscripts package has a modular IP
    assignment format, and creating additional files in the <filename
    class="directory">/lib/services/</filename> directory allows other IP
    assignment methods. This is commonly used for Dynamic Host Configuration
    Protocol (DHCP), which is addressed in the BLFS book.</para>

    <para><envar>SERVICE</envar>はIPアドレスを取得するための方法を定義します。
    LFS-Bootscriptsパッケージはモジュール化されたIP割り当ての形式を持っており、<filename class="directory">/lib/services/</filename>ディレクトリに追加のファイルを作成することで、他のIP割り当て方法を追加することが出来ます。
    これは一般にDHCP(Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol)で使用され、BLFSブックの中で取り扱っています。</para>

    <para>The <envar>GATEWAY</envar> variable should contain the default
    gateway IP address, if one is present. If not, then comment out the
    variable entirely.</para>
    <para><envar>GATEWAY</envar>は、もし存在するならば、デフォルトゲートウェイのIPアドレスをセットします。
    もしセットしなければ、変数を完全にコメントアウトしてください。</para>

    <para>The <envar>PREFIX</envar> variable needs to contain the number of
    bits used in the subnet. Each octet in an IP address is 8 bits. If the
    subnet's netmask is 255.255.255.0, then it is using the first three octets
    (24 bits) to specify the network number. If the netmask is 255.255.255.240,
    it would be using the first 28 bits.  Prefixes longer than 24 bits are
    commonly used by DSL and cable-based Internet Service Providers (ISPs).
    In this example (PREFIX=24), the netmask is 255.255.255.0. Adjust the
    <envar>PREFIX</envar> variable according to your specific subnet.</para>
    <para><envar>PREFIX</envar>はサブネットとして使用するビットの数をセットします。
    IPアドレスのそれぞれのオクテットは8ビットです。
    もしサブネットマスクが255.255.255.0であれば、ネットワークアドレスの指定に、最初の3つのオクテット(24ビット)を使用します。
    24ビットを越えるPrefixは、一般にDSLやケーブルのISP(Internet Service Provider)で使用されます。
    この例では(PREFIX=24)、ネットマスクは255.255.255.0となります。
    ここではあなたのサブネットに合わせて<envar>PREFIX</envar>の設定を調整してください。</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="resolv.conf">
    <!--<title>Creating the /etc/resolv.conf File</title>-->
    <title>/etc/resolv.confファイルの作成 </title>

    <indexterm zone="resolv.conf">
      <primary sortas="e-/etc/resolv.conf">/etc/resolv.conf</primary>
    </indexterm>

    <para>If the system is going to be connected to the Internet, it will
    need some means of Domain Name Service (DNS) name resolution to
    resolve Internet domain names to IP addresses, and vice versa. This is
    best achieved by placing the IP address of the DNS server, available
    from the ISP or network administrator, into
    <filename>/etc/resolv.conf</filename>. Create the file by running the
    following:</para>
    <para>もしシステムをインターネットに接続するつもりであれば、ドメイン名からIPアドレスを引くために、DNS(Domain Name Service)の名前解決の手段が必要になります。
    これを実現する最良の方法は、ISPまたはネットワーク管理者から得られるDNSサーバのIPアドレスを<filename>/etc/resolv.conf</filename>に設定することです。
    このファイルを次の通り作成します：</para>

<screen><userinput>cat &gt; /etc/resolv.conf &lt;&lt; "EOF"
<literal># Begin /etc/resolv.conf

domain <replaceable>&lt;Your Domain Name&gt;</replaceable>
nameserver <replaceable>&lt;IP address of your primary nameserver&gt;</replaceable>
nameserver <replaceable>&lt;IP address of your secondary nameserver&gt;</replaceable>

# End /etc/resolv.conf</literal>
EOF</userinput></screen>

    <para>The <varname>domain</varname> statement can be omitted 
    or replaced with a <varname>search</varname> statement.  See the man page for 
    resolv.conf for more details.</para>
    <para><varname>domain</varname>の行は省略したり、<varname>search</varname>行に置き換えることが出来ます。
    より詳細の情報は、resolv.confのmanページを参照してください。</para>

    <para>Replace <replaceable>&lt;IP address of the nameserver&gt;</replaceable>
    with the IP address of the DNS most appropriate for the setup. There will
    often be more than one entry (requirements demand secondary servers for
    fallback capability). If you only need or want one DNS server, remove the
    second <emphasis>nameserver</emphasis> line from the file. The IP address
    may also be a router on the local network.</para>
    <para><replaceable>&lt;IP address of the nameserver&gt;</replaceable>を最も適したDNSのIPアドレスに置き換えてください。
    大抵は1つ以上のDNSを登録します(万が一のため、2つ目のサーバを必要とする)。
    もし1つのDNSサーバだけでいい場合、ファイルから2番目の<emphasis>nameserver</emphasis>を削除してください。
    IPアドレスはローカルネットワークのルータかもしれません。</para>

    <note>
      <para>The Google Public IPv4 DNS addresses are 8.8.8.8 and 8.8.4.4.</para>
      <para>GoogleのパブリックIPv4 DNSサーバアドレスは、8.8.8.8と8.8.4.4です。</para>
    </note>

  </sect2>

</sect1>
