<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>
<!-- revision 8929 -->

<sect1 id="pre-audience">
  <?dbhtml filename="audience.html"?>

  <title>読者へ</title>

<para>There are many reasons why you would want to read this book. One of the
questions many people raise is, <quote>why go through all the hassle of manually
building a Linux system from scratch when you can just download and install
an existing one?</quote></para>
<para>あなたがこのLFSブックを読みたいと思う理由はたくさんあるでしょう。
多くの人々から寄せられる質問の一つに、<quote>ダウンロードしてインストールできる既存のディストリビューションがあるのに、どうしてLinuxシステムを一から構築するような面倒なことをするのですか？</quote>があります。</para>

<para>One important reason for this project's existence is to help you learn
how a Linux system works from the inside out. Building an LFS system helps
demonstrate what makes Linux tick, and how things work together and depend on
each other. One of the best things that this learning experience can provide is the ability to customize a Linux system to suit your own unique needs.</para>
<para>LFSが存在する一つの重要な理由は、Linuxがどのように動いているか、徹底的に学ぶための手助けになるということです。
LFSシステムを構築することにより、何がLinuxを動かしているのか、どのような仕組みで動いているのか、また、それらがどのように依存しているのかを理解しやすくなります。
LFSシステムの構築を経験することによって得られる一番のものは、Linuxシステムを自分独自のニーズに合ったものにカスタマイズする能力を得られることです。</para>

<para>Another key benefit of LFS is that it allows you to have more control
over the system without relying on someone else's Linux implementation. With
LFS, you are in the driver's seat and dictate every aspect of the
system.</para>
<para>LFSのその他の大きな利点は、他人が構築したLinuxの制限に引っかかることなく、システム全体をよりコントロールできるようになることです。
LFSなら、あなたは運転席に座っているようなもので、システムのあらゆる仕様を決めることが出来ます。</para>

<para>LFS allows you to create very compact Linux systems. When installing
regular distributions, you are often forced to install a great many
programs which are probably never used or understood. These programs waste
resources. You may argue that with today's hard drive and CPUs, such
resources are no longer a consideration. Sometimes, however, you are still
constrained by size considerations if nothing else. Think about bootable
CDs, USB sticks, and embedded systems. Those are areas where LFS can be
beneficial.</para>
<para>LFSではとてもコンパクトなLinuxシステムを作ることが出来ます。
普通のディストリビューションであれば、おそらく決して使わないか、知らないような非常に多くのプログラムが強制的にインストールされてしまいます。
それらプログラムはリソースを消費してしまいます。
今日のハードディスクやCPUにおいて、そのようなリソースはもはや心配するようなことではないとあなたは反論するかもしれません。
しかしながら、いまだ容量の制約を受けることが時々あります。
ブータブルCD、USBスティック、組み込みシステム等を考えてみてください。
LFSが有益であるのは、そのような領域です。</para>

<para>Another advantage of a custom built Linux system is security. By compiling
the entire system from source code, you are empowered to audit everything
and apply all the security patches desired. It is no longer necessary to
wait for somebody else to compile binary packages that fix a security hole.
Unless you examine the patch and implement it yourself, you have no
guarantee that the new binary package was built correctly and adequately
fixes the problem.</para>
<para>カスタムビルドのLinuxシステムのもう一つの利点は、セキュリティです。
全てのシステムをソースコードからコンパイルすることによって、システム全てを検査することが出来るようになります。
また、必要なセキュリティパッチ全てを適用することも出来ます。
誰かが、セキュリティホールを塞いだバイナリパッケージをコンパイルするまで待つ必要は、もはや無くなります。
ただし、あなたがパッチと実装内容を自身でチェックしなければ、新しいバイナリパッケージが正しくビルドされ、適切に問題が解消される保証はありません。</para>

<para>The goal of Linux From Scratch is to build a complete and usable
foundation-level system. If you do not wish to build your own Linux system
from scratch, you may not entirely benefit from the information in this
book.</para>
<para>Linux From Scratchのゴールは、完全で使い物になる基盤レベルのシステムを構築することです。
もし、あなたが自分自身のLinuxシステムを一から作りたいと思わないのであれば、この本の情報から完全に利益を得られないかもしれません。
</para>

<para>There are too many other good reasons to build your own LFS system to 
list them all here. In the end, education is by far the most powerful of
reasons. As you continue in your LFS experience, you will discover the power
that information and knowledge truly bring.</para>
<para>自分自身のLFSシステムを構築することについて、その他良い理由が多すぎるため、ここで全ての理由を列挙することができません。
とはいえ、結局は教育が最も強力な理由となります。
LFSについての経験を続けることによって、情報や知識が真にもたらす力を発見することでしょう。</para>

</sect1>
