<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>
<!-- revision 8929 -->

<sect1 id="pre-typography">
  <?dbhtml filename="typography.html"?>
  
  <title>文章の体裁</title>

  <para>To make things easier to follow, there are a few typographical
  conventions used throughout this book. This section contains some
  examples of the typographical format found throughout Linux From
  Scratch.</para>

  <para>文章を読みやすくするため、いくつかの表記上のルールを定めます。
  このセクションではそれらいくつかの書式について説明します。</para>

<screen role="nodump"><userinput>./configure --prefix=/usr</userinput></screen>

  <para>This form of text is designed to be typed exactly as seen unless
  otherwise noted in the surrounding text. It is also used in the explanation
  sections to identify which of the commands is being referenced.</para>
  <para>この書式は、特に注記がない限り、見たままを正確に入力する必要があるテキストを示しています。この書式は、コマンドの説明を行うセクションでも使用されます。</para>

  <para>In some cases, a logical line is extended to two or more physical lines 
  with a backslash at the end of the line.</para> 
  <para>いくつかのケースにおいて、論理的な1行は、行末のバックスラッシュにより2行以上になります。</para>

<screen role="nodump"><userinput>CC="gcc -B/usr/bin/" ../binutils-2.18/configure \ 
  --prefix=/tools --disable-nls --disable-werror</userinput></screen> 

  <para>Note that the backslash must be followed by an immediate return.  Other 
  whitespace characters like spaces or tab characters will create incorrect 
  results.</para>
  <para>バックスラッシュは、直後にリターンが必要です。
  バックスラッシュの直後にスペースやタブのような空白の文字が続くと、おかしな結果になります。</para>

<screen><computeroutput>install-info: unknown option '--dir-file=/mnt/lfs/usr/info/dir'</computeroutput></screen>

  <para>This form of text (fixed-width text) shows screen output, usually as
  the result of commands issued.  This format is also used to show filenames,
  such as <filename>/etc/ld.so.conf</filename>.</para>

  <para>この固定幅フォントの書式は、通常、コマンドの実行結果等の画面出力を表しています。この書式はまた、/etc/ld.so.confのようなファイル名を表す場合にも使わます。</para>

  <para><emphasis>Emphasis</emphasis></para>

  <para>This form of text is used for several purposes in the book. Its main
  purpose is to emphasize important points or items.</para>

  <para>この書式は本書ではいくつかの目的で使われます。この書式を用いる主な目的は、重要なポイントもしくは物事を強調することです。</para>

  <para><ulink url="&lfs-root;"/></para>

  <para>This format is used for hyperlinks both within the LFS community and to
  external pages. It includes HOWTOs, download locations, and websites.</para>

  <para>この書式はハイパーリンクを表す。例えば、HOWTO、ダウンロードリンク、ウェブサイトです。</para>

<screen role="nodump"><userinput>cat &gt; $LFS/etc/group &lt;&lt; "EOF"
<literal>root:x:0:
bin:x:1:
......</literal>
EOF</userinput></screen>

  <para>This format is used when creating configuration files. The first command
  tells the system to create the file <filename>$LFS/etc/group</filename> from
  whatever is typed on the following lines until the sequence End Of File (EOF)
  is encountered. Therefore, this entire section is generally typed as
  seen.</para>

  <para>この書式は設定ファイルを作成する際に用いられます。
  1行目のコマンドは、"EOF"が現れるまでにタイプされた内容を <filename>$LFS/etc/group</filename> に書き込みます。したがって、上記内容は見たままを入力することになります。</para>

  <para><replaceable>&lt;REPLACED TEXT&gt;</replaceable></para>

  <para>This format is used to encapsulate text that is not to be typed
  as seen or for copy-and-paste operations.</para>
  
  <para>この書式はそのまま入力するものではなく、環境に応じて置き換えを行う必要がある場合に用いられます。</para>

  <para><replaceable>[OPTIONAL TEXT]</replaceable></para>

  <para>This format is used to encapsulate text that is optional.</para>

  <para>この書式は任意のオプションを示しています。</para>

  <para><filename>passwd(5)</filename></para>

  <para>This format is used to refer to a specific manual (man) page. The number inside parentheses
  indicates a specific section inside the manuals. For example,
  <command>passwd</command> has two man pages. Per LFS installation instructions,
  those two man pages will be located at
  <filename>/usr/share/man/man1/passwd.1</filename> and
  <filename>/usr/share/man/man5/passwd.5</filename>. When the book uses <filename>passwd(5)</filename> it is
  specifically referring to <filename>/usr/share/man/man5/passwd.5</filename>.
  <command>man passwd</command> will print the first man page it finds that
  matches <quote>passwd</quote>, which will be
  <filename>/usr/share/man/man1/passwd.1</filename>. For this example, you will
  need to run <command>man 5 passwd</command> in order to read the specific page
  being referred to. It should be noted that most man pages do not have duplicate
  page names in different sections. Therefore, <command>man <replaceable>&lt;program
  name&gt;</replaceable></command> is generally sufficient.</para>

  <para>この書式は指定したマニュアル(man)ページへの参照を示しています。
  括弧内の数字はマニュアルのセクション番号を表しています。
  例えば、<command>passwd</command>コマンドは2つのmanページを持っています。
  LFSの導入手順においては、<filename>/usr/share/man/man1/passwd.1</filename>と<filename>/usr/share/man/man5/passwd.5</filename>の2つのmanページが存在します。
  本書で<filename>passwd(5)</filename>と表記されている場合は、<filename>/usr/share/man/man5/passwd.5</filename>を明確に指しています。
  <command>man passwd</command>を実行すると、<quote>passwd</quote>でマッチする最初に見つかったmanページが表示されます。
  おそらく<filename>/usr/share/man/man1/passwd.1</filename>が表示されると思います。
  上記例では、<command>man 5 passwd</command>を実行する必要があります。
  ただし、ほとんどコマンドは複数のセクションにmanページを持ちません。
  したがって、<command>man <replaceable>&lt;program name&gt;</replaceable></command>で大抵は問題ないです。</para>
</sect1>

