<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>
<!-- revision 9408 -->

<sect1 id="materials-introduction">
  <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>

  <title>イントロダクション</title>

  <para>This chapter includes a list of packages that need to be downloaded in
  order to build a basic Linux system. The listed version numbers correspond to
  versions of the software that are known to work, and this book is based on
  their use. We highly recommend against using newer versions because the build
  commands for one version may not work with a newer version. The newest package
  versions may also have problems that require work-arounds. These work-arounds
  will be developed and stabilized in the development version of the
  book.</para>

  <para>この章では、基礎となるLinuxシステムを構築するためにダウンロードが必要なパッケージのリストを記載しています。
  リストされたパッケージのバージョンは、動作確認されたソフトウェアのバージョンです。また、本書ではそれらバージョンのパッケージの使用を前提としています。
  より新しいバージョンを使用することは推奨しません。それは、あるバージョンのビルドコマンドが、新しいバージョンでは動かない可能性があるからです。
  また、最新バージョンでは、対処が必要な問題があるかもしれません。
  それら対処は、本書の開発バージョンにて開発・安定化が行われるでしょう。
  </para>

  <para>Download locations may not always be accessible. If a download
  location has changed since this book was published, Google (<ulink
  url="http://www.google.com/"/>) provides a useful search engine for
  most packages. If this search is unsuccessful, try one of the
  alternative means of downloading discussed at <ulink
  url="&lfs-root;lfs/packages.html#packages"/>.</para>

  <para>もしかするとダウンロードのロケーションは、アクセスが出来なくなっているかもしれません。
  本書がリリースされた後にダウンロードのロケーションが変わった場合は、Google (<ulink url="http://www.google.com/"/>)がパッケージのロケーションを探すためのサーチエンジンとして役立つでしょう。
  検索がうまくいかない場合、<ulink url="&lfs-root;lfs/packages.html#packages"/>にある別のロケーションを試してみてください。
  </para>

  <para>Downloaded packages and patches will need to be stored somewhere
  that is conveniently available throughout the entire build. A working
  directory is also required to unpack the sources and build them.
  <filename class="directory">$LFS/sources</filename> can be used both
  as the place to store the tarballs and patches and as a working
  directory. By using this directory, the required elements will be
  located on the LFS partition and will be available during all stages
  of the building process.</para>

  <para>ダウンロードされたパッケージとパッチは、構築を通じて利用可能な場所に格納しておく必要があります。
  作業用のディレクトリも、ソースの展開やビルドで必要となります。
  <filename class="directory">$LFS/sources</filename>は、tarballやパッチを格納する場所として、また、作業用ディレクトリとして使用されます。
  このディレクトリを使うことにより、必要な構成要素はLFSパーティションに置かれ、LFS構築の全てのステージにおいて利用できます。
  </para>

  <para>To create this directory, execute the following command, as user
  <systemitem class="username">root</systemitem>, before starting the download
  session:</para>

  <para>このディレクトリを作成するため、<systemitem class="username">root</systemitem>ユーザで以下コマンドを実行してください。
  </para>

<screen role="nodump"><userinput>mkdir -v $LFS/sources</userinput></screen>

  <para>Make this directory writable and sticky. <quote>Sticky</quote>
  means that even if multiple users have write permission on a
  directory, only the owner of a file can delete the file within a
  sticky directory. The following command will enable the write and
  sticky modes:</para>

  <para>このディレクトリは、書き込み可能およびStickyに設定してください。
  <quote>Sticky</quote> の意味は次の通りです。たとえ複数のユーザが書き込み権限を持っていても、Stickyに設定したディレクトリに存在するファイルは、そのファイルの所有者のみが削除可能となります。
  以下のコマンドで、書き込み可能およびStickyモードが有効になります。

  </para>

<screen role="nodump"><userinput>chmod -v a+wt $LFS/sources</userinput></screen>

  <para>An easy way to download all of the packages and patches is by using 
  <ulink url="../wget-list">wget-list</ulink> as an input to 
  <command>wget</command>. For example:</para>
  <para>全てのパッケージとパッチをダウンロードする簡単な方法は、<ulink url="../wget-list">wget-list</ulink>を<command>wget</command>コマンドの入力として使うことです。例：</para>
  <screen role="nodump"><userinput>wget -i wget-list -P $LFS/sources</userinput></screen>
</sect1>
