<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>
<!-- revision 9067 -->

<sect1 id="ch-system-aboutdebug">
  <?dbhtml filename="aboutdebug.html"?>

  <!--<title>About Debugging Symbols</title>-->
  <title>デバッグシンボルについて</title>

  <para>Most programs and libraries are, by default, compiled with
  debugging symbols included (with <command>gcc</command>'s
  <parameter>-g</parameter> option). This means that when debugging a
  program or library that was compiled with debugging information
  included, the debugger can provide not only memory addresses, but also
  the names of the routines and variables.</para>
  <para>ほとんどのプログラムとライブラリは、デフォルトでデバッグシンボルを含む形でコンパイルされます(<command>gcc</command>の<parameter>-g</parameter>オプション)。
  デバッグ情報付きでコンパイルされたプログラムやライブラリをデバッグする際、デバッガはメモリアドレスだけでなく、ルーチンや変数の名前も提供してくれます。</para>

  <para>However, the inclusion of these debugging symbols enlarges a
  program or library significantly. The following is an example of the
  amount of space these symbols occupy:</para>
  <para>しかしながら、デバッグシンボルの付加によって、プログラムやライブラリのサイズがかなり増えてしまいます。
  以下は、デバッグシンボルが占めるスペースの量の例です。
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>A <command>bash</command> binary with debugging symbols:
      1200 KB</para>
      <para>デバッグシンボル付きの<command>bash</command>バイナリ：1200 KB</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>A <command>bash</command> binary without debugging symbols:
      480 KB</para>
      <para>デバッグシンボルなしの<command>bash</command>バイナリ：480 KB</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Glibc and GCC files (<filename class="directory">/lib</filename>
      and <filename class="directory">/usr/lib</filename>) with debugging
      symbols: 87 MB</para>
      <para>デバッグシンボル付きのGlibcとGCCのファイル(<filename class="directory">/lib</filename>と<filename class="directory">/usr/lib</filename>)：87 MB</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Glibc and GCC files without debugging symbols: 16 MB</para>
      <para>デバッグシンボルなしのGlibcとGCCファイル：16 MB</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Sizes may vary depending on which compiler and C library were used,
  but when comparing programs with and without debugging symbols, the
  difference will usually be a factor between two and five.</para>
  <para>使用するコンパイラやCライブラリによって、サイズは変わりますが、デバッグシンボルの有無でプログラムサイズを比較すると、通常は2-5倍の差が出ます。</para>

  <para>Because most users will never use a debugger on their system software,
  a lot of disk space can be regained by removing these symbols. The next
  section shows how to strip all debugging symbols from the programs and
  libraries.</para>
  <para>ほとんどのユーザは自分のシステムソフトウェアにおいて、決してデバッガを使用しないため、デバッグシンボルを取り除くことで、多くのディスクスペースを取り戻すことが出来ます。
  次のセクションでは、プログラムやライブラリから全てのデバッグシンボルをストリップする方法を紹介します。</para>
  

</sect1>
